Hi, this is David Duke.
In this clip I'm going to talk about carrying the glider.
I have it balanced on my shoulders about at the edge of the deltoid right here.
Each wing is about the size of a hobicat sail, so you can imagine the power that wings can generate if you get them into the wind wrong.
So this is the correct way to pick it up turn it around.
And your instructor will go over all of this.
Do not get your nose too high or you'll go over backwards.
And now we're into the wind.
And the glider is actually in this wind it's pretty much flying right now.
So it's really not much weight on my shoulders.
These hands here are used to control my nose angle, so I can actually steer the glider as it is flying right here even, just as I would in the sky.
We can check that we're hooked one more time.
Again, I'm noticing that I'm not in my backup, but we're not going to do that today.
So then I want to use the wind to actually help me walk back up this little training slope we have here.